Brendah Nyanchama Onsombi

+254741170937

nyanchamabrendah3@gmail.com https://github.com/nyanchamaB

PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

Brendah is dedicated in technology profession with expertise in areas like software development and system management. She is committed to using her skills to benefit the community. She actively participates in volunteer programs, mentorship and educational initiatives to empower underrepresented groups.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programs Intern, Riziki Source (May 2024 – Present)

- Part of the team leading in conducting accessibility testing for workplace Learning Management System (LMS) to support companies and job seekers.
- Recruited the first cohort of 40 trainees for Jiandae virtual training (2024) on workplace etiquette and CV crafting.
- Part of the team participated in creating disability awareness in 3 Vocation training colleges, from each institution, we registered more than 5 individuals with disabilities for the organization's various training programs to prepare them into the field of work.

Modern Technology researcher & Global Advisor volunteer, Billion Strong (Aug 2023 – April 2024)

- Part of Billion Strong policy change which has allowed more than 500 persons with disabilities from Africa to participate in assistive technology development volunteer work and mentorship programs.
- Participated in a one month training on user accessibility and global standards for generative AI model development education conducted by research department in partnership with google.

Open source developer & Tester, Kaggle Humanitarian (June 2023)

• Contributed in the open-source development and testing GETTA model which works to learn new skills and solve open-ended questions.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology, Kenyatta University (2021 – Present)

Certificate of completion in networking, Cisco Academy (May 2022 – July 2023)

Kenya Certificate Secondary Education, Nyabururu Girls' High School (2016 – 2020)

SKILLS

- Programming skills
 - Front-end development (HTML, CSS, Dart, JavaScript, React)
 - -Back-end development (Node.Js, Java, SQL, Firebase)
 - -Frameworks (Flutter, Angular)
- Data entry
- Collaboration and negotiation
- Learning and adaptability
- User support

HOBBIES

Modern adaptive technologies research

Mental health mentorship

Playing chess and darts

REFEREES

Jean Auko, Riziki Source: jean@rizikisource.org

Chris Kanyi, Professional Certification Hub: manmaish@gmail.com

Dr. John Kandiri, Lecturer Kenyatta University: jkandiri@gmail.com